Five hundred seventy-one million
571 مليون
two hundred thirty thousand pounds of paper towels
و 230 ألف رطل من المناشف الورقية
are used by Americans
تستخدم من قبل الأميركيين
every year.
كل سنة.
If we could -- correction, wrong figure --
لو استطعنا -- تصحيح، رقم خاطئ --
13 billion used every year.
13 مليار تستخدم كل سنة.
If we could reduce the usage of paper towels,
إن استطعنا التقليل من استخدام المناشف الورقية،
one paper towel per person per day,
منشفة ورقية للشخص الواحد في اليوم،
571,230,000 pounds of paper not used.
571,230,000 رطل من الورق غير المستخدم.
We can do that.
يمكننا أن نفعل ذلك.
Now there are all kinds of paper towel dispensers.
هناك الآن أنواع كثيرة من موزعات المناشف الورقية.
There's the tri-fold. People typically take two or three.
هناك المطوية ثلاث مرات. الناس عادة يأخذون اثنين أو ثلاثة.
There's the one that cuts it, that you have to tear off.
هناك تلك التي تقطع، والتي عليك تمزيقها.
People go one, two, three, four, tear.
يأخذ الناس واحدة واثنتين وثلاثة وأربعة ثم يمزقون.
This much, right?
هذا القدر، أليس كذلك؟
There's the one that cuts itself.
هناك تلك التي تمزق نفسها.
People go, one, two, three, four.
يأخذ الناس واحدة واثنتين وثلاثة وأربعة.
Or there's the same thing, but recycled paper,
أو هناك نفس الشيء، لكن بالورق المعاد تدويره،
you have to get five of those because they're not as absorbent, of course.
عليك أخذ خمسة منها لأنها لا تمتص بنفس القدر، بطبيعة الحال.
The fact is, you can do it all with one towel.
والحقيقة، يمكنك أن تفعل كل شيء بمنشفة واحدة.
The key, two words:
المفتاح، كلمتان:
This half of the room, your word is "shake."
هذا النصف من الغرفة، كلمتكم هي "نفض".
Let's hear it. Shake. Louder.
دعونا نسمع ذلك. نفض. أعلى صوتا.
Audience: Shake.
الجمهور: نفض.
Joe Smith: Your word is "fold."
جو سميث: كلمتكم هي "طي".
Audience: Fold.
الجمهور: طي.
JS: Again.
ج. س: مرة أخرى.
Audience: Fold. JS: Really loud.
الجمهور: طي. ج. س: بصوت أعلى.
Audience: Shake. Fold.
الجمهور: نفض. طي.
JS: OK. Wet hands.
ج. س: حسنا. أيدي مبللة.
Shake -- one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12.
نفض - واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة، أربعة، خمسة، ستة، سبعة، ثمانية، تسعة، 10، 11، 12.
Why 12? Twelve apostles, twelve tribes,
لماذا 12؟ رسل المسيح الإثني عشر، القبائل الإثني عشر،
twelve zodiac signs, twelve months. The one I like the best:
الأبراج الإثني عشر، إثنا عشر شهرا. وتلك التي أحب أكثر:
It's the biggest number with one syllable.
هو أكبر رقم من مقطع واحد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Tri-fold. Fold ...
طي ثلاثي. طي...
Dry.
تجفيف.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Audience: Shake.
الجمهور: نفض.
Fold.
طي.
JS: Cuts itself. Fold. The fold is important
ج. س: تمزق نفسها. طي. الطي مهم
because it allows interstitial suspension.
لأنه يسمح بتعليق خلالي.
You don't have to remember that part, but trust me.
ليس عليكم تذكر ذلك الجزء، ولكن ثقوا بي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Audience: Shake. Fold.
الجمهور: نفض. طي.
JS: Cuts itself.
ج. س: تمزق نفسها.
You know the funny thing is,
تعرفون، الأمر المضحك هو،
I get my hands drier than people do with three or four,
يمكنني تجفيف يدي أكثر ممن يستخدم ثلاثة أو أربعة،
because they can't get in between the cracks.
لأنهم لا يستطيعون الوصول إلى ما بين الشقوق.
If you think this isn't as good...
إذا كنت تعتقد أن هذا ليس بنفس الجودة...
Audience: Shake. Fold.
الجمهور: نفض. طي.
JS: Now, there's now a real fancy invention,
ج. س: الآن، هناك الآن اختراع حقيقي ممتاز،
it's the one where you wave your hand
وهو ذلك الذي تلوّح فيه بيديك
and it kicks it out.
ويقوم بالنفض.
It's way too big a towel.
لكنه منشفة كبيرة جدا.
Let me tell you a secret.
اسمحوا لي أن أخبركم بسر.
If you're really quick, if you're really quick --
إذا كنت سريعا حقاً، إذا كنت سريعا حقا -
and I can prove this --
وأستطيع إثبات هذا -
this is half a towel from the dispenser in this building.
هذه نصف منشفة من الموزع في هذا المبنى.
How? As soon as it starts, you just tear it off.
كيف؟ بمجرد بدء تشغيله، تقوم فقط بتمزيقها.
It's smart enough to stop.
إنها ذكية بما فيه الكفاية للتوقف.
And you get half a towel.
ويمكنك الحصول على نصف منشفة.
Audience: Shake. Fold.
الجمهور: نفض. طي.
JS: Now, let's all say it together. Shake. Fold.
ج. س: الآن، دعونا نقل كل ذلك معا. نفض. طي.
You will for the rest of your life remember those words
وستتذكرون تلك الكلمات لبقية حياتكم
every time you pick up a paper towel.
في كل مرة تلتقطون فيها منشفة ورقية.
And remember, one towel per person for one year --
وتذكر، منشفة واحدة للشخص الواحد في السنة -
571,230,000 pounds of paper. No small thing.
571,230,000 رطل من الورق. ليس بالأمر الهين.
And next year, toilet paper.
في السنة المقبلة، ورق الحمام.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)